consumerbase.com 2010-11-25

# Privacy Policy | ConsumerBase.com

Last Updated: November 2003

Organ Worldwide, LLC, [ConsumerBase LLC](http://www.consumerbase.com/Home-page.html), eShopFirst, ConsumerWireless, Offerz.com, DegreeLinks, Email Lookup, Reports 2008, Official Referral, Value Seekers, BehaviorBase and ResponderInfo as well as affiliates, divisions, contractors and all data sources and suppliers, all of which are referred to herein as "The Company” has a deep commitment to the privacy of every individual about whom it holds information. Since we gather individual [consumer data](http://www.consumerbase.com/Data-Cards.html), we want users to fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather, how we use it, and how we correct or change it.

Each mail list vendor at the Company asserts that protecting consumer privacy is our greatest concern. We pledge to conduct our business according to the following principles:

 **Consumer Rights**  
The Company understands the always-changing legalities and courtesies regarding the use and dissemination of our customers’ information.

 **Compliance**  
Each mail list broker at The Company actively monitors all local laws in order to be compliant with any regulatory requirement.

 **Ethical Relationships**  
Each mail list vendor at The Company pledges to conduct our relationships with both clients and other information providers in an ethical and professional manner.

 **Awareness**  
The Company is committed to education for our clients, our employees and the industry about the issues, guidelines and laws surrounding individual consumer rights to privacy and The Company’s privacy policies.

 **Accuracy**  
Mail list brokers at The Company maintain strict quality control and due diligence procedures to assure the integrity and accuracy of our information.

 **Security**  
Mail list vendors at The Company maintain strict security procedures to ensure information will not be made available to any unauthorized person or business.

 **Consumer Benefits**  
The Company offers services and information products that provide benefits to both consumers and businesses.

 **Information Gathering and Tracking**  
The Company captures consumer information from own websites and through opt-in co-registration from our vendors. This information is typically obtained through our own, or our vendors' sites in connection with a user's registration. The information captured allows for more targeted offers to consumers.

 **Use of Information**  
The Company uses any information obtained in order to provide users with information on products and/or services that may be of interest to them.

We may enhance or merge users’ personally identifiable information with data collected from other sources to use in direct or online marketing, including the data services described in "Sharing of Information" below. In the event we enhance or merge personally identifiable information with data collected from other sources, we will take all necessary steps to maintain the integrity and quality of that information.

 **Sharing of Information**  
The Company uses the information described above to help our clients better understand the demographics of their target audiences as well as to support our marketing of data products and services. Each list vendor at the Company may provide personally identifiable data to marketing companies, advertising agencies, data compilers, data companies, and, to the extent permitted by law, individual reference and look-up service programs. Such information may be used by such companies to provide consumers with information on products and services that may be of interest.

If consumers in our database have indicated that they do not want to have their data shared with third parties, The Company will limit the use of their data to the suppression, validation and enhancement of existing information held by third parties about its users. For example, marketers may use data about a registrant provided by The Company, such as "opt-out" information, to suppress or drop the registered user's name from a file of potential customers. Additional information may be used to verify and/or validate the accuracy of existing data on the registrant that was lawfully acquired by a marketer. In addition, our data customers may use data supplied by The Company to enhance or [append](http://www.consumerbase.com/Email-Appends.html) personally identifiable data to their file for use in direct or [online marketing](http://www.consumerbase.com/Search-Engine-Marketing.html) subject to the terms of their own privacy policies.

Exceptions may occur in the event of a merger, acquisition, sale of assets of The Company or any of its divisions as a going-concern, or change of control, in which case such data would be considered a business asset and would be transferred subject to the terms of this privacy policy. Nonetheless, our users will always have the opportunity to choose whether or not they want to receive further information and offers from any division within The Company or our marketing partners.

 **Opt-out/Unsubscribe Policy**  
By registering with our or our vendors' sites to receive third party offers, users allow The Company and its affiliates to make their personally identifiable information available to third parties in accordance with the terms of this privacy policy. The Company provides users the option to opt-out from receiving information sent on behalf of third party advertisers by our internal affiliates or to opt-out from The Company and its divisions sharing information with advertisers or third party marketers for promotional purposes. Notwithstanding, all personally identifiable information provided by a user may be used by The Company to support its marketing data services business described above.

Users may unsubscribe to electronic mailings sent via our internal affiliates at any time by following the instructions contained at the end of every newsletter or emailing. Users may opt-out of receiving further information sent on behalf of third party advertisers by The Company or from The Company sharing information with advertisers or third party marketers for promotional purposes. Currently, mail list brokers at The Company do not offer users a means by which to completely delete personal data in order to maintain a master suppression file.

Please note that information sent on behalf of third party advertisers is prepared days in advance, so users may continue to receive email from The Company for up to 7-days after they have un-subscribed.

 **Security Policy**  
The Company maintains security guidelines to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of information in its database. Access to personally identifiable information is only provided to authorized employees of The Company. Mail list vendors at The Company are made aware of our security guidelines during our employee orientation process. Our security guidelines are reviewed at least quarterly based on our fiscal calendar.

With any specific questions regarding our privacy policy, we can be reached via email at [a='privacy@';b='consumerbase.com/">privacy@consumerbase.com](http://mailto:<script type=). The Company takes online privacy extremely seriously, and does not share the information users have submitted without their permission.

 **Consumer Advocacy**  
We have a Privacy Advocate that is available to assist our users with any privacy concerns they may have. Our privacy advocate will take each individual’s concerns seriously and will ensure that any necessary steps are taken to resolve any potential conflicts. Our privacy advocate supervises the “unsubscribe” process and ensure that such consumers are removed from our email lists within 7-days, and individually assist in various issues regarding consumer privacy.

 **Internal Monitoring**  
Our Privacy Advocate also ensures that all aspects of our privacy policy are upheld. All employees receive the appropriate training and resources to ensure privacy compliance, and we regularly monitor our security protocols, and handle any concerns regarding our employees’ compliance with our privacy principles and policy.

 **Contact Information**  
Our Consumer Privacy Advocates may be reached via e-mail or postal mail:  
Privacy Department  
ConsumerBase LLC  
1603 Orrington Avenue, Floor 9  
Evanston, IL 60201-3841  

Version 1.0

For more information about our privacy policies, contact a [mail list broker](http://www.consumerbase.com/Contact.html) at ConsumerBase today or [request a quote](http://consumerbase.com/quote/starthereT6';c='.php';%20document.write\(a+b+c\);%3C/script%3E).
